Guide to the Charles Seymour, President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles Seymour, president of Yale University, records
1917-1956
RU 23
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
85.25
(207 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, reports, memoranda, planning records, minutes of meetings, speeches, and biographical clippings documenting all aspects of Charles Seymour"s activities as president of Yale University.
Yale University. President's Office
Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of the President, 1958.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, reports, memoranda, planning records, minutes of meetings, speeches, and biographical clippings documenting all aspects of Charles Seymour's activities as president of Yale University.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Seymour was born in New Haven, Connecticut on January 1, 1885. He attended Cambridge (B.A. 1904, M.A. 1909), Yale (B.A. 1908, Ph.D. 1911) and the University of Paris. Seymour taught history at Yale from 1911-1937. In 1937 he became president of Yale, a position he held until 1950. Seymour inaugurated the Directed Studies Program for freshmen and sophomores, revived the Scholar of the House Program, and introduced such interdepartmental majors as Foreign Area and American Studies. In addition to his duties at Yale he served as chief of the Austro-Hungarian Division of the American Commission to Negotiate Peace; U.S. delegate on the Rumanian, Jugoslavian, and Czechoslovakian Territorial Commissions (1919); and curator of the Edward House Collection at Yale (1923-1963). Seymour died in Chatham, Massachusetts on August 11, 1963.
Arrangement
The records are arranged as follows: I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1917-1954. II. War Emergency Planning Records, 1938-1947. III. Post-war Planning Board Records, 1943-1945. IV. Council of Masters Minutes, 1937-1950. V. Addresses, Speeches, and Biographical Clippings.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; College presidents; Educators; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Presidents; Yale University. President's Office
- Correspondence and subject files, 1917-1954 1937-1950; 1937-1950; Series I
  - A - AK, 1938-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbott, Charles C. and Wilbur C., 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acheson, Dean G., 1937-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Officers, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Organization Committee
    General note
    See: box 54, folder 474
  - Administrative Principles: memorandum, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Admissions, Board of: Chairman, Edward Simpson Noyes, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Admissions, Board of: individual cases, post-war, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
  - Admissions, Board of: miscellaneous, 1939-1950 (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
  - Admissions, Sub-committee on Methods of, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Admissions, Trip: "Flying Squadron" Northern Illinois, 1945, February 12-28 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Airplane Accident Seattle, 1949, January 2
    See: box 154, folder 1295
  - Al, 1939-1950 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Alumni Associations and Yale Clubs, 1937-1950 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Alumni Associations and Yale Clubs, 1937-1950 (Box 3, Folder 19-23)
  - Alumni Associations and Yale Clubs: greetings, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Alumni Associations and Yale Clubs: New Haven Alumni Association, 1937-1950 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Alumni Associations and Yale Clubs: President"s letter to, 1937 September 30 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Alumni Associations and Yale Clubs: Yale Club of Boston, 1944-1950 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Alumni Associations and Yale Clubs: Yale Club of Havana, 1945-1949 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Alumni Associations and Yale Clubs: Yale Club of New York, 1940-1946 (Box 4, Folder 29-29a)
  - Alumni Board, 1937-1950 (Box 4, Folder 30-32)
    See also: box 165, folder 1415
  - Alumni Board, 1937-1950 (Box 5, Folder 33-35)
  - Alumni Board: Acting Executive Secretary, George Dudley Vaill, 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Alumni Board: Alumni Award, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Alumni Board: Board of Visitors, 1940-1941 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Alumni Board: Chairman, John B. Dempsey, 1940-1944 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Alumni Board: Chairman, Albert D.Farwell, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Alumni Board: Chairman, John Marshall Holcombe Jr., 1937-1941 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Alumni Board: Committee for the Nomination of Alumni Fellows, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Alumni Board: Committee on Alumni Forums, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Alumni Board: Committee on Coordination of Alumni Affairs, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Alumni Board: Committee on Enrollment and Scholarships, 1937-1950 (Box 6, Folder 45-47)
  - Alumni Board: Committee on Memorials, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Alumni Board: Committee on Publicity and Public Relations, 1938-1942 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Alumni Board: Conference, 1940 July 11 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Alumni Board: Convocation, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Alumni Board: Dodge, Marshall Jr., 1940 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Alumni Board: Executive Committee, 1938-1948 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Alumni Board: Executive Secretary, Russell L. Bradley, 1943-1948 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Alumni Board: Executive Secretary, Sumner McKnight Corsby "32, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Alumni Board: Executive Secretary, Harold Leighton Fates, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Alumni Board: Executive Secretary, C. Hamilton Sanford, Jr. "28S, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Alumni Board: Executive Secretaryship, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Alumni Board: Graduate Placement Bureau, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    See: box 117, folder 995
  - Alumni Board: Sunday Forum, 1941 June 15 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Alumni Board: Survey Committee, Yale Personnel Register, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Alumni Board: The Yale Alumni Forum, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Alumni Board: Yale Alumni War Service Committee, 1942-1946 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Alumni Class Gift Committee
    See: box 165, folder 1417
  - Alumni Council, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Alumni (University) Day, 1938-1950 (Box 7, Folder 65-67)
  - Alumni (University) Day: comments on address, 1948 February (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Alumni (University) Day: broadcast, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Alumni Fellows: nominations, ballots, etc., 1937-1950 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Alumni Fund, 1937-1950 (Box 8, Folder 71-74)
  - Alumni Fund, 1937-1950 (Box 9, Folder 75-77)
    See also: box 165, folder 1416
  - Alumni Fund: Committee on Bequests, 1941-1943 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Alumni Fund: Fiftieth Anniversary, (1939)-1940 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Alumni Fund: insurance plan, class gift, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Alumni Fund: Special Gifts Committee, 1942-1945 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Alumni News Release
    See: box 166, folder 1426
  - Alumni Organization
    See: box 163, folder 1376
  - Alumni Relations, Director of, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Alumni Relations: Director Ogden D. Miller, 1937-1941 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Alumni Relations: Mr. Seymour"s letter sent to special groups in regard to Mr. Miller having been appointed Director of, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Alumni Relations: suggestions for director, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Alumni Relations Committee
    See: box 147, folder 1235
  - Alumni trips, 1939-1944 (Box 10, Folder 86-88)
  - Alumni trips: California, Hawaii and Canada, 1940-1941 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Alumni trips: California, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Alumni trips: West, 1942 April 28-May (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Alumni trips: Dallas, 1943 May 25-31 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Alumni trips: Rochester, Buffalo, Cleveland, Chicago, St. Paul, 1945 April (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Alumni trips: Pacific Coast and Hawaii, 1947 February-April (Box 11, Folder 94-95)
  - Alumni trips: South and Middle West, 1948 February-March (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Alumni trips: Pittsburgh, 1948 April-May (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - Alumni trips: South-Southwest, 1949 March (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - Alumni trips, 1949 Spring (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - Alumni trips: Cleveland, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - Alumni trips: special letters to school masters who went to Chicago, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Alumni trips: taken by administrative officials and faculty, 1938-1950 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - Am, 1939-1949 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - American Academy of Arts and Science, 1940-1950 (Box 13, Folder 104-105)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 106)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1941-1950 (Box 13, Folder 107)
  - American Association of Museums, 1937-1942 (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1937-1949 (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - American Association of University Women, 1938-1944 (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - American Cancer Society, 1947-1950 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - The American Churches and the International Situation, 1939-1943 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - American Council of Learned Societies: general correspondence and fellowship grants, 1937-1950 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - American Council on Education, 1937-1950 (Box 14, Folder 114-118)
  - American Council on Education: Advisory Committee on College testing, Cooperative Test Service, 1943, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - American Federation of Labor, Local 142
    See: box 126, folder 1064-1065
  - American Forum of Democracy, 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 120)
  - American Journal of Science, 1926-1946 (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - American Peace Committee, 1942 July 23 (Box 15, Folder 122)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1939-1950 (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - American Red Cross, 1942-1950 (Box 15, Folder 124)
  - American Social Hygiene Society, 1937-1940 (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1937-1941 (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - American Studies, Program of [Gabriel], 1945-1950 (Box 15, Folder 127-128)
  - American University Union in Europe, 1937-1942 (Box 15, Folder 129)
  - American Veterans Committee: Yale chapter, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 130)
  - Americans United, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 131)
  - An, 1937-1949 (Box 16, Folder 132)
  - Andrews, Mrs. James P., 1941-1942 (Box 16, Folder 133)
  - Angell, J.R. - Seymour correspondence, 1937-1950 (Box 16, Folder 134)
  - Angier, Roswell P., 1938-1946 (Box 16, Folder 135)
  - Anthropology, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 16, Folder 136)
  - Ap - Ar, 1938-1950 (Box 16, Folder 137)
  - Applications for positions at Yale, 1938-1950 (Box 16, Folder 138)
  - Appointments, Bureau of
    See: box 33, folder 291
  - Architectural Plan Committee
    See: box 53, folder 463
  - Armistice Day service, 1937-1949 (Box 16, Folder 139)
  - Allison Armour bequest [ for Davenport College ], 1941 (Box 16, Folder 140)
  - Art Gallery, 1940-1950 (Box 16, Folder 141)
  - Art Gallery Committee
    See: box 163, folder 1379
  - Art Gallery: New wing, other building needs, art school, 1940-1950 (Box 17, Folder 142)
  - Art School, 1937-1950 (Box 17, Folder 143-145)
  - Art School: Associates in Fine Arts at Yale, 1944-1950 (Box 17, Folder 146)
  - Art School: Committee on successor to Dean Meeks, 1946-1947 (Box 17, Folder 147)
  - Art School: Dean Sawyer correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 17, Folder 148)
  - Art School: Focillon, Prof. and Mme. Henri, 1937-1949 (Box 17, Folder 149)
  - Art School: Housing Conference, Dept. of Architecture - Life Magazine - Architecture Forum, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 150)
  - Art School: industrial camouflage course (under the auspices of the Dept. of Architecture), 1942 (Box 18, Folder 151)
  - Art School: Moore, Mrs. Paul, 1942-1949 (Box 18, Folder 152)
  - Art School: Prix de Rome Prize, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 153)
  - Art School: program for education in the history of fine arts, 1939-1941 (Box 18, Folder 154)
  - Art School: Rabinowitz "Declaration of Trust" re: gift to Yale of his collection of pictures, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 155)
  - Arts, Division of the, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 156)
  - Arts, Division of the, Committees
    See: box 163, folder 1380
  - Arts and Sciences, Faculty of
    See: box 68, folder 588
  - As - Az, 1941-1950 (Box 18, Folder 157)
  - Asakawa, K
    See: box 82, folder 713
  - Asia Institute, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 158)
  - Assistant Secretaries, 1940-1946 (Box 18, Folder 159)
  - Associates in the Science of Society, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 160)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1938-1948 (Box 18, Folder 161-162)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1938-1948 (Box 19, Folder 163)
  - Association of American Colleges: Commission on Liberal Education, 1942-1945 (Box 19, Folder 164)
  - Association of American Colleges: Commission on Wartime Placement of College Faculties, 1942-1943 (Box 19, Folder 165)
  - Association of American Universities, 1937-1949 (Box 19, Folder 166-168)
  - Association of Colleges in New England, 1937-1949 (Box 20, Folder 169-171)
  - Astronomy, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 20, Folder 172)
  - Athletics: Agreements, Eight College, Committee on Administration Committee on Eligibility, 1945-1950 (Box 20, Folder 173)
  - Athletics: Agreements, Eight College, regulation of intercollegiate football Conference - New York, 1944 November 15 (Box 21, Folder 174-175)
  - Athletics: Agreements, Yale-Harvard-Princeton, 1925-1943 (Box 21, Folder 176-177)
  - Athletics: Agreements, Yale-Harvard-Princeton, opening day for football practice, eligibility, 1938-1945 (Box 21, Folder 178)
  - Athletics: Athletic Association
    See: box 25, folder 209
  - Athetics: Board of Control [Athletic Association], 1937-1950 (Box 22, Folder 179-180)
    note: Director of Athletics and Chairman of the Athletic Association Board of Control may be a joint position.
  - Athletics: Board of Control, Chairman, Malcolm Farmer [Athletic Association], 1937-1946 (Box 22, Folder 181)
  - Athletics: Board of Control, letters regarding Mr. Farmer"s successor [Athletic Association], 1939-1940 (Box 22, Folder 182-184)
  - Athletics: Board of Control, minutes [Athletic Association], 1947-1950 (Box 22, Folder 185)
  - Athletics: Constitution and By-Laws, 1917-1940 (Box 22, Folder 186)
  - Athletics: Crew, 1938-1950 (Box 23, Folder 187)
  - Athletics: Director, appointment of, 1946, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 188-189)
  - Athletics: Director, R.J.H.Kiphuth, 1938-1950 (Box 23, Folder 190)
  - Athletics: Director, Clarence W. Mendell, 1939-1940 (Box 23, Folder 191)
  - Athletics: Director, Ogden D.Miller, 1940-1946 (Box 23, Folder 192)
  - Athletics: Director, successor to Mr. Miller, 1945-1946 (Box 23, Folder 193)
  - Athletics: Football, 1937-1950 (Box 23, Folder 194-196)
  - Athletics: Football, Army Game, 1937-1943 (Box 24, Folder 197)
  - Athletics: Football, coach, Raymond W. Pond, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 198)
  - Athletics: Football: coaching situation, 1941-1948 (Box 24, Folder 199-200)
  - Athletics: General, 1937-1950 (Box 24, Folder 201)
  - Athletics: Gymnasium Committee, 1938-1946 (Box 24, Folder 205)
  - Athletics, Inter-College
    See: box 158, folder 1336-1337
  - Athletics: National Collegiate Athletic Association, 1939-1950 (Box 25, Folder 206)
  - Athletics: Yale Bowl, 1937-1948 (Box 25, Folder 207)
  - Athletics: Yale Football Y Association, 1942-1950 (Box 25, Folder 208)
  - Athletics: Yale University Athletic Association: budget and financial statements, 1937-1944 (Box 25, Folder 209)
  - Athletics: Yale University Athletic Association, Business Manager, H.F.Woodcock, 1943-1944 (Box 25, Folder 210)
  - Atomic Bomb: correspondence regarding, 1945-1949 (Box 25, Folder 211)
  - Atterbury, Grosvenor
    See: box 83, folder 727
  - Atterbury superheated, precast, sectional concrete system, 1930-1950 (Box 25, Folder 212)
  - Audio-visual Service, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 213)
  - Aurelian Honor Society, 1937-1949 (Box 25, Folder 214)
  - Aviation Club (also Rocket Club), 1937 (Box 25, Folder 215)
  - B, 1938-1947 (Box 25, Folder 216)
  - Babylonian Collection, 1938 (Box 25, Folder 217)
  - Bak, 1938-1949 (Box 25, Folder 218)
  - Baldwin, Gov. Raymond E., 1942-1948 (Box 25, Folder 219)
  - Bar, 1937-1949 (Box 26, Folder 220)
  - Bas, 1937-1948 (Box 26, Folder 221)
  - Be, 1937-1948 (Box 26, Folder 222)
  - Belgian American Educational Foundation, 1937-1950 (Box 26, Folder 223-224)
  - Belgian American Educational Foundation, 1937-1950 (Box 27, Folder 225)
  - Bell, Ulrich
    See: box 113, folder 960
  - Bellamy, F.Wilder, Jr., Memorial Prize, 1941-1946 (Box 27, Folder 226)
  - Ben, 1939-1949 (Box 27, Folder 227)
  - Ber, 1938-1949 (Box 27, Folder 228)
  - Berden, John, Memorial Gift, 1941, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 229)
  - Berkeley College
    See: box 155, folder 1303-1304
  - Berkeley Divinity School, 1938-1949 (Box 27, Folder 230)
  - Berlin Conference on German War Documents report, 1947 July 3-6 (Box 27, Folder 231)
  - Bi, 1937-1950 (Box 27, Folder 232)
  - Biblical Literature
    See: box 44, folder 379
  - Biological Sciences Committee
    See: box 147, folder 1236
  - Billings, Blanche E. Macheish Memorial Award, 1938-1949 (Box 27, Folder 233)
  - Bingham, Jonathan B., 1949-1950 (Box 27, Folder 234)
  - Bingham Oceanographic Foundation
    See: box 124, folder 1054
  - Biological Sciences, Division of, 1939-1950 (Box 27, Folder 235)
  - Biophysics: Interdepartmental group, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 236)
  - Birth control, 1938, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 237)
  - Bishop Museum, 1937-1948 (Box 28, Folder 238)
  - Bishop Museum Committee, 1937-1950 (Box 28, Folder 239)
  - Bl, 1938-1950 (Box 28, Folder 240)
  - Blair, Edwin Foster, 1940-1950 (Box 28, Folder 241)
  - Blair, William McC., 1941-1947 (Box 28, Folder 242)
  - Blue Network Broadcast, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 243)
  - Bo, 1937-1949 (Box 29, Folder 244)
  - Board of Admissions
    See: box 1, folder 6
  - Bollingen Prize in Poetry
    See: box 98, folder 838
  - Bor - Boy, 1937-1950 (Box 29, Folder 245-246)
  - Bra, 1938-1950 (Box 29, Folder 247)
  - Bradley, Russell L.
    See: box 7, folder 54
  - Bradford, Arthur H., 1937-1950 (Box 29, Folder 248)
  - Branford College
    See: box 156, folder 1308
  - Bri, 1937-1950 (Box 29, Folder 249)
  - British Council, 1944 (Box 30, Folder 250)
  - Bro, 1937-1950 (Box 30, Folder 251-252)
  - Broadcasting, Committee on, 1940 (Box 30, Folder 253)
  - Browder, Earl: speech at Yale, 1939-1940 (Box 30, Folder 254)
  - Browder, Earl: speech at Yale: letters of approval, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 255-256)
  - Browder, Earl: speech at Yale: letters of protest, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 257)
  - Browder, Earl: speech at Yale: letters of protest, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 258)
  - Browder, Earl: speech at Yale: letters, second time, 1939-1940 (Box 31, Folder 259)
  - Browder, Earl: speech at Yale: newspaper articles, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 260)
  - Brown University, 1938-1948 (Box 31, Folder 261)
  - Brown, William Adams, 1937-1943 (Box 31, Folder 262)
  - Bu, 1937-1950 (Box 31, Folder 263)
  - Buck, Paul
    See: box 137, folder 1156
  - Buck, Dr. Peter H. (Bishop Museum), 1932-1937 (Box 31, Folder 264)
  - Buckner, Mortimer N., 1937-1942 (Box 31, Folder 265)
  - Budget, 1937-1950 (Box 31, Folder 266-269)
  - Budget, 1944-1945 (Box 32, Folder 270)
  - Budget: materials for Corporation meeting, 1945 February 10 (Box 32, Folder 271)
  - Budget, 1945-1947 (Box 32, Folder 272-273)
  - Budget: meeting, 1947 November 26 (Box 32, Folder 274)
  - Budget, 1947-1949 (Box 32, Folder 275-276)
  - Budget: including Scholarship Committee material, 1949-1950 (Box 32, Folder 277)
  - Budget: D.G.Acheson"s: analysis of income and expenses, educational and administrative, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 278)
  - Budget: annual departmental budgets, 1929-1946 (Box 32, Folder 279)
  - Budget: economy program, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 280)
  - Budget: general administration costs, 1936-1948 (Box 32, Folder 281)
  - Budget: statements, 1940-1950 (Box 32, Folder 282)
  - Buildings: use of, 1937, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 283)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee
    See: box 53, folder 465
  - Bur - By, 1939-1950 (Box 32, Folder 284)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Citizens" Military Training Camps (CMTC) Scholarships, 1937-1941 (Box 33, Folder 285)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), 1934-1940 (Box 33, Folder 286)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Department of Personnel Study, 1937-1950 (Box 33, Folder 287-288)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Educational Aptitude Testing Program (Carnegie Corporation), 1938-1944 (Box 33, Folder 289)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Freshman Scholarship Committee, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 290)
  - Bureau of Appointments: general, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 291)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Graduate Record Examination Program, 1938-1946 (Box 33, Folder 292)
  - Bureau of Appointments: increased freshman class and scholarship situation, 1941-1942 (Box 33, Folder 293)
  - Bureau of Appointments: National Youth Administration, 1937-1943 (Box 33, Folder 294)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Scholarships and Fellowships, 1938-1950 (Box 34, Folder 295-297)
  - Bureau of Appointments: special scholarship folder, 1942 (Box 34, Folder 298)
  - Bureau of Appointments: student charges, scholarship allocations, 1940-1942 (Box 34, Folder 299)
  - Bureau of Appointments: survey of student employment, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 300)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Undergraduate Scholarship Committee of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, 1941-1942 (Box 34, Folder 301)
  - Bureau of Appointments: Yale Scholarship Trust of Chicago (Box 34, Folder 302)
  - Bureau of Highway Traffic, 1938-1950 (Box 35, Folder 303-304)
  - Bureau of Highway Traffic: Automotive Safety Foundation correspondence, 1938-1943 (Box 35, Folder 305)
  - Bursar's Office - F.B.Johnson, 1937-1948 (Box 35, Folder 306)
  - Bursary Appointments Committee
    See: box 156, folder 1316
  - Bush, Prescott S., 1938-1950 (Box 35, Folder 307)
  - C, 1937-1949 (Box 35, Folder 308)
  - Cabinet, undated (Box 35, Folder 309)
  - Cabinet: minutes, 1937-1941 (Box 35, Folder 310-313)
  - Cabinet: minutes, 1941-1942 (Box 36, Folder 314)
  - Cabinet officers: minutes, 1942-1950 (Box 36, Folder 315)
  - Calendar, University, 1938-1950 (Box 36, Folder 316)
  - Calhoun College
    See: box 156, folder 1309
  - Campbell, Hugh: estate of, 1939-1946 (Box 36, Folder 317)
  - Canby, Henry S., 1937-1950 (Box 36, Folder 318)
  - Car, 1937-1950 (Box 36, Folder 319)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1937-1950 (Box 36, Folder 320)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1945-1946 (Box 36, Folder 321)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching: Pensions, etc., 1937-1945 (Box 37, Folder 322)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1941-1944 (Box 37, Folder 323)
  - Cartography Laboratory, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 324)
  - Cas, 1937-1948 (Box 37, Folder 325)
  - Central University Organization, 1937 (Box 37, Folder 326)
  - Ch, 1937-1949 (Box 37, Folder 327-328)
  - Chapel, 1937-1950 (Box 37, Folder 329)
  - Chapel: Episcopal chaplain and students: Brewster Memorial, 1938-1949 (Box 37, Folder 330)
  - Chapel, Battell: Committee on renovation of, 1945-1948 (Box 37, Folder 331)
  - Chapel, Battell: organ committee, 1950 (Box 38, Folder 332)
  - Chemistry, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 38, Folder 333)
  - Cheney, Howell, 1937-1948 (Box 38, Folder 334)
  - Chi, 1937-1950 (Box 38, Folder 335-336)
  - Chicago, University of, 1937-1949 (Box 38, Folder 337)
  - Child Welfare Research Fund
    See: box 106, folder 894
  - Childs, Jane Coffin, Memorial Fund for Medical Research, 1937-1950 (Box 39, Folder 338-342)
  - Childs, Jane Coffin, Memorial Fund for Medical Research, 1937-1950 (Box 40, Folder 343)